bendigobank.com.au 2006-06-16

# Bendigo Bank - Privacy and Security Statement

## This Privacy and Security Statement contains important information about your personal information. You will be informed about:

  1. Customer Privacy Policy; 
  2. Collection of personal information; 
  3. Use and disclosure of personal information; 
  4. Overseas transactions; 
  5. Access and correction; 
  6. Opting out of product promotions; 
  7. Storage and security of your personal information; 
  8. Bendigo Bank Group website and the use of cookies; 
  9. Changes to this policy; 
  10. Privacy concerns or complaints; 
  11. Contacting us;

##  Customer Privacy Policy 

Bendigo Bank Group is committed to ensuring your privacy is protected and understands your concerns regarding the confidentiality and security of personal information you provide to us.

This Customer Privacy Policy sets out how we safeguard your privacy.

Most organisations in Australia must comply with 10 National Privacy Principles. We are bound by and comply with these principles.

In this policy, references to Bendigo Bank Group or the Group are to Bendigo Bank Limited and its subsidiaries, agencies and franchises (including Community Bank branches).

## Collection of personal information

We collect personal information that includes details such as name, address, date of birth, contact details (such as phone and fax numbers, e-mail addresses) and financial information about you such as information about your use of financial products and services which you acquire from or through us.

In some cases, we may need to collect sensitive information (such as health related information) about you. In these circumstances we will ask for your consent to collect that information if the National Privacy Principles require that we do so. 

In most cases, you provide the Group with your information. Sometimes we collect or confirm this information from a third party such as a credit reporting agency. Generally we will have sought your consent to do this.

## Use and disclosure of personal information

We use your personal information in order to provide you with financial products and services. To do that, we may disclose your personal information to organisations that carry out functions on the Group's behalf, such as mailing houses, cheque and electronic transaction processors and information technology service providers. Confidentiality agreements with these entities ensure this information is only used to carry out functions on the Group's behalf. Depending upon the type of product you have requested, we may also disclose your personal information to credit reporting agencies, the trustee or manager of a superannuation fund and insurance companies. 

Our other uses of your personal information may include the Group's regular and necessary business functions such as internal audit investigations, performance reporting, research, product development and planning.

Bendigo Bank Group does not sell your personal information to outside companies. It may be shared within the Bendigo Bank Group and our joint venture partners so that you can be told about other financial products and services offered or distributed by us. You can opt out of receiving this information (see below).

## Overseas transactions

In some cases, your personal information may be transferred overseas. For example, when you instruct us to carry out a transaction such as a telegraphic transfer to or from an overseas country. We will only transfer your personal information overseas with your consent or in a way which is otherwise consistent with our obligations under the Privacy Act.

## Access and correction 

In most cases you will be able to gain access to personal information about you held by the Group. We will take reasonable steps to amend or correct your personal information to keep it accurate and up-to-date. Our Customer Help Centre will co-ordinate requests relating to access and correction of your personal information.

## Opting out of product promotions

You can opt at any time not to receive any marketing from us about new products. If you do opt out, we will continue to provide information in relation to your existing accounts only (including new features or products related to these accounts).

## Storage and security of your personal information

Bendigo Bank Group will take reasonable steps to keep personal information about you that it holds and uses secure, accurate and up-to-date. Your personal information is stored within secure systems that are protected in controlled facilities. Our employees and authorised agents are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by the Group.

## Bendigo Bank Group website and the use of cookies

The Bendigo Bank Group website is protected by 128-bit encryption technology and it uses cookies. Cookies are very small text files that a website can transfer to your computer's hard drive for record keeping. Cookies can make using our website easier by storing information about your preferences and enabling you to take full advantage of our services. 

Most Internet web browsers are pre-set to accept cookies to enable full use of websites that employ them. However, if you do not wish to receive any cookies you may configure your browser to reject them or warn you when cookies are being used. In some instances, this may mean that you will not be able to use some or all of the services provided on our website. However you may still be able to access information only pages.

## Changes to this Policy

From time to time, it may be necessary for us to review our Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to amend our Privacy Policy at any time and to notify you by posting an updated version on the Bendigo Bank Group website (www.bendigobank.com.au).

## Privacy concerns or complaints

If you have concerns or wish to make a complaint regarding the treatment of your personal information by Bendigo Bank Group please contact our Customer Help Centre for assistance. 

## Contacting us

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, or about the way we manage your personal information:

  * You can write to us at: 

> Bendigo Bank   
>  Customer Help Centre   
>  PO Box 480   
>  Bendigo Vic 3552 

  * You can telephone Customer Help Centre on 1300 361 911
  * You can e-mail us at [customerhelpcentre@bendigobank.com.au](mailto:customerhelpcentre@bendigobank.com.au)

Date of Publication - 20th December 2001  

* * *

Copyright © Bendigo Bank Limited ABN 11 068 049 178
